Email: Karey.w.wong@gmail.com

COMPENSATION LEADER

COMPETITIVE ANALYSIS & REPORTING/ COMPLEX DATA SET ANALYSIS

15+ years' experience in optimizing data driven comp programs, benchmarking, designing incentive models, creating performance criteria matrix + bonus pool funding scale + career architecture framework from scratch. Proven record to provide highly effective solutions to business stakeholders by navigating through ambiguity, and presenting data in "big picture" vs "small picture" to pinpoint top challenges from top bottom to make strong recommendations to influence decision making,

	SKIES
Survey Tools	Market Pay, Payfactor, Payscale, Towers Watson, Aon Hewitt, Radford, Croner, CTHRA, Culpepper, Hay Group, Payscale, Robert Half, Mercer Win, Nucleus, Deloitte, PWC, ERI, Pay Net, 4As, Equilar, PR Week, eMsight
Tech Skills	Advance Excel: Functional and Procedure VBA (Macros); Power Pivot, Complex Nested Formulas, Index Double Match Power BI and Tableau: SQL, Building Stories, Measurement and Dashboard Creations GIT HUB
Applications	Project Management App: Asana, Jira, MS Project, Confluence, Agile Craft, TFS, Connect IT, Footprints Google Tools: Plx, Nucleus, gComp, Prosper, PopsConnect, Buganizer, gThanks, Stadio, and Navigo
Certificates	CCP, Workday, Excel, SQL, Financial Modeling, PMP, CSM, ASM, SPC4, Six-Sigma Greenbelt

SKILLS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

GOOGLE (Tech Industry)

<u>Director Program Manager L5, HR Compensation</u>

Feb 2022 - Present

- Oversee the automation of Benchmarking + Year-End Merit + Bonus + Stock Granting with a team of 60 Compensation Analysts and 12 Engineers. Combine stakeholder input, industry best practices, and data analytics insights to have an impact on leadership choices. Streamline business processes, increase efficiency and automation at scale (without alienating people).
- Synthesize data insights to organize, anticipate, and communicate risks in a timely manner to mitigate future issues.
- Lead cross-functional program team representing Engineering, Comms, Finance, and HR to deliver promotion cycles (twice a year) for over 16,000 Googlers globally. Lead the annual merit and bonus planning cycle for over 187,000 employees globally.
- Promote Employee Referral (5 Peer Spot Bonuses + 5 Manager Spot Bonuses per quarter) Program with a focus on launching global projects and strategic initiatives to improve user experience, engage employees, and improve operations.
- Initiated, planned, controlled, executed, monitored, tested, and implemented Market Job Pricing Tool called Nucleus.
- Manage system, tool, and feature enhancement requests for Benchmarking, Vendor, Recognition, and Promotion programs.
- Guide team of Engineers, Analysts, and External Vendors to deliver streamlined program to save 500 hours annually while preserving market competitiveness. Manage Market Pricing Program to achieve Google's Principals/philosophy.
- Managed Project Charters, Roadmaps, Project Timelines, Project Plans, BRDs, Change Management Trainings, and SLAs.
- Gather technical requirements from HR and work with Tech to update algorithms, configurations, and reporting requests.
- Point of contact for vendors such as Deloitte, EY, PWC, Radford, Aon Hewitt, Mercer, Tower Watson, Croner, Culpepper, etc.

CROTHERS (Consulting Industry)

Sr. Consultant, HR (1099)

Part Time- Present

- Financial Modeling to automate Company's Revenue Growth, Net Sales, Net Profits, EBITDA, or EBITA (Formula Writing, Formula Auditing, Projection, Forecasting, Scenario Manager, Net Present Value-NPV, Internal Rate of Return-IRR, etc.).
- Train Recruitment and People Consultant teams how to create internal/ external job descriptions and KPIs/ OKRs from scratch.

- Build Company, Department, and Individual Performance Criteria Matrix from scratch with start-up Chief Executive Officers.
- Establish compensation philosophies tied to startup business strategy to support their rapid growth with links to recruiting and retention strategy. Review clients' current compensation programs, historical pay practices, job postings/descriptions to recommend best practices and market pay recommendations. Build career frameworks in partnership with Leadership and HR.
- Redesign companies' variable bonuses, incentives, and pay for performance programs integrated with performance appraisal initiatives. Recommend implementation of various plan designs, build excel model, create, and revise plan documentations.
- Conduct FLSA Exempt Testing; Identify Pay Equity (diversity, gender, age, race, location, etc.) and Pay Compression issues.

UNIVISION (Media Industry)

Director, HR Compensation

Jan 2021 - Feb 2022

- Introduced a high-performance culture program that reallocated incentives to top performers and trained 2k+ Managers.
- Led a \$500k career redesign initiative involving 250 leaders decreasing jobs from 7k to 750k and grades from 36 to 16.
- Created global career paths that decreased voluntary turnover, increased internal mobility by 8%, and reduced turnover costs by \$3 M within the first year. Achieved a 7% improvement in employee satisfaction scores while increasing pay equity.
- Oversaw annual compensation review process to ensure appropriate accruals, processing and payments were made.
- Managed team of US and International Compensation Analysts to lead Univision Compensation Programs.

<u>WPP</u> (Ads + Marketing Industry)

Sr. Manager, HR Compensation

May 2019 - Jan 2021

- Provided guidance and support for all compensation related matters (Equity, Stock Options, RSU, PSU, STI, Commission, Benchmarking, Career Framework, Workday Job Profiles Creation, Comp Planning for 190,000+ employees globally).
- Led Year End Salary and Bonus Programs in partnership with Local, Regional, and Country MDs, CHROs and CFOs.
- Reviewed Covid salary sacrifices, incentive summary roll ups, STIP cash submissions, PSA, One off award submissions.
- Managed Annual Leaders and Partners Awards, Performance Share Plans, Executive Share Performance Nominations, Oneoff Restricted Stock Units, Make Good Awards, and conducted SEC Proxy Analysis in preparation for Comp Board meetings.

TRIBUNE MEDIA (Media Industry)

Manager, HR Compensation

Jan 2017- May 2019

- Led the design, development, and administration of compensation programs such as the annual cash incentive plans, merit budgets, job evaluations, salary structures and market analysis. Managed performance and salary administration programs to retain a competitive compensation posture in the marketplace. Led year-end bonus and salary (merit) planning process.
- Conducted job evaluation and managed survey processes including matching interpretation and communication to determine the company competitive pay position. Participated in Market Surveys (Mercer, Towers Watson, Radford).
- Built an advanced comp module in Workday. Managed the creation of grade profiles, positions, comp plans, eligibility rules, job profiles, business processes, and approval workflows, custom reports, dashboards, comp, and merit grids.
- Implemented Market Pay salary benchmarking tool. Executed market data end-to-end process, collaborated with internal resources for the submission of accurate data; Assessed and prepared market survey results for analysis related to compensation structures, merit increases and total rewards. Managed contractual relationships with survey vendors.

CHEAP O'AIR (Tech Industry)

March 2015- Jan 2017

Team Leader, Finance Compensation

- Created and deployed annual incentive plans for 4,000 employees in the US, India, Germany, and Ukraine that were competitive, and compliant with company direction, local laws, pay equity or other statutory requirements.
- Managed all reporting on performance metrics and trends in headcount, diversity turnover/retention, mobility, talent management, recruitment, competitive landscape, and career progression.
- Conducted Job Analysis, FLSA Exempt Testing, Market Evaluation, Salary Administration to determine the appropriate Salary Structure (pay ranges) and Job Pricing based on internal and external equity. Subject Matter Expert in Federal + State laws.
- Designed user-friendly SLA processes, guidelines, documentation for Workday users to better promote the consistent use and data integrity of the system, and to help support the HR, Comp, Benefits, Performance, and Recruitment processes.

DAVID YURMAN (Retail Industry)

Sr. Analyst, Finance Compensation

June 2011- March 2015

- Led the design and implementation of a new employee incentive and commission program, resulting in 100% automation of calculations and generation of audit reports. As part of daily HR operations, managed and maintained all compensation plans, promotions, market adjustments, and discretionary payouts. Managed compensation plans for U.S, Thailand, France, and UK
- Managed all aspects of DY's comp benchmarking and market pricing initiatives. This included overseeing the participation in salary surveys (Hay Group, Payne, World at Work) to ensure competitive pay practices, benchmarked positions to support compensation strategies, and understanding industry developments, competitor pay practices and general industry trends.
- Created and updated job descriptions for new and existing positions when required. Collaborated with staffing and business clients to assist in hiring, retention, development of employees. Partnered with Payroll to process bonus, merit, and additional compensation related inquiries. Collaborated with HR Managers and Generalists to provide support for clients' issues.
- Designed and executed a successful Organizational Change Management plan for Workday HCM that rolled out to all employees resulting in 100% adoption rate in the first 3 months of production implementation.

EDUCATION

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY

- Data Analytics
- Al Machine Learning

PACE UNIVERSITY

• Finance

OUEENS COLLEGE

- Psychology
- Urban Studies

REFERENCES

GOOGLE

Manager: Kenneth Chan

Personal Mobile: 917-306-0216 (PST)Personal Email: <u>Kennchan@gmail.com</u>

• Peer: Nikolaus Klassen

o Personal Mobile: 720-320-9424 (MST)

o Personal Email: Nikolaus.klassen83@gmail.com

CROTHERS

Manager: <u>Laura Osborn</u>

o Personal Mobile: 201-317-0512 (EST)

o Work Email: <u>Laura@crothershrconsulting.com</u>

UNIVISION

• Manager: Sharon Bulanhagui

o Personal Mobile: 917-439-5994 (EST)

o Personal Email: <u>Bulanhagui917@gmail.com</u>

Peer: Diane Persaud

Personal Mobile: 646-316-9099 (EST)Personal Email: Dpersaud87@gmail.com